西班牙怎么样？
How is Spain?
完全没假日，这是肯定的
No holiday. That's for sure.
那房子绝对闹鬼
The house was definitely haunted
一个三百年的老鬼
A 300 year old ghost.
问题在于George，我那个客户
The trouble was George, my client.
那鬼没恶意，但我觉得没能完全说服他
I don't think I completely convinced him
the ghost was friendly.
- 这些外国人真恐怖 - 你还说这个，不是你让我去的？
- Bloody foreigners.
- You say that? But you sent me.
我是升职了，但不代表我对你的关心少了
Just because I got promoted, doesn't say I care about your less
是，Patsy，但我们还是尽量把咱们的私人关系
Yes, Patsy. But let's try
and keep our personal relationships simple
跟工作区分开来，好不？
from a professional way, shall we?
噢，你总看到事情不好的一面
Oh, you looked at the wrong side of the plain(??)
不管怎样，超自然研究局(PROBE)还在可靠的人手里
Well anyway, the Preternatural Research Bureau is in safe hands
事实上我有点东西要给你
In fact I have something for you
就在后座上
on the back seat
军队实验项目？真的吗？
An army experiment? really?
我知道你不太喜欢，但是...
I know its not your favorite, but...
你需要第三方意见
You need a second opinion.
是，我觉得是需要
Yes, I guess I do
不说这个了
Enough of that
刚才你是怎么说私人关系这事的？
what were you saying about personal relationships?
惨了
Shit
是 Williams
Williams
这个得接
Goona take this.
我再打给你
I'll call you.
好的
All right.
PROBE 5: When to Die
超自然研究局 第五集 何时逝去
听录/翻译：巴蛮子sz
（听力/翻译水平有限，请多包涵）
我的名字是下士7891阿尔法
My name is corporal 7891-alpha
也叫 Paul Reynish
a.ka. Paul Reynish
下面是我的故事
and this is my story
我成人之后一直都在军队里面
I've been in the army all my adult life
已经呆了很久了
and that's a very long time
非常久
a very long time
那么
So,
我为什么这么特殊？
what's so special about me?
没什么，真的
Nothing. really
只除了一件事
Except for one thing
时间
Time
我手上有全世界的时间
all the time in the world on my hands
我是国防部的一项秘密实验品
I'm the covert MOD experiment
一项延长寿命的实验
the one of tests into longevity
我也曾在波斯尼亚呆过
I was in Bosnia, too
作为一个不会老化的军需品
as a never-aging military asset
放下武器
Lower your weapon.
就是那时我认识了 Josie
That is when I met Josie
但 Josie 并不长久
But Josie didn't last
她还有其他的鱼要钓
She had other fish to fry
很滑稽的是，即便过了这么多年
Its funny, but after all these years,
关于凡事都有好有坏这一点，我仍在学着接受
I'm still learning to take the rough with the smooth.
我觉得自己算是幸运的
I suppose I should consider myself lucky
对，我知道我消耗了国防部数百万
Well, I know I'm costing the MOD millions
这主要用来生产这些小玩意
That's how much it takes to process these little babies
它们是用火星陨石材质制成的
They're made from a martian meteorite
他们是这么跟我说的
So they tell me
我并不懂它们为什么有效，但是...
I don't understand how they work. but...
的确有效
They do.
快点
Come on
你明天还有大事
You got a big day tomorrow
上床吧
Come to bed
好的，大老板
All right, Bossy boots
你明天会陪我去
You'll be there tomorrow, won't you?
靠！
Fuck!
没事吧？
Everything ok?
没事
I'm fine.
早上好，Shaw 博士
Morning, Dr. Shaw.
Morning.
早上好
嘿，你回来啦。怎么样？
Hey, you're back. How was that? (??)
我不知道，爱谁谁吧
I don't know, somebody out there.
哇噢，你在哪里找到的
Wow, where did you find it?
在仓储区，Smith 博士那个架子上
In the storage hold.
On the Dr. Smith's shelf.
John Smith。是叫 John Smith 博士
John Smith, Dr. John Smith.
是盒子，一直都不能用
It's Box, and never worked
是，但，我会修好它
Yeah, well, I'm gonna fix it.
祝你好运，Gilles
Good luck, Gilles.
那是什么？
Whats that?
重要任务
Priority job
又来一个？
And another one?
Liz, 我们积压的任务都有手臂长了
Liz, we got a case load as long as your arm.
我知道，但这个很重要
I know, but this is important.
Giles
好吧
All right.
- 从哪儿开始？  - 这里
- Where do we start?  - Here.
当我不在战场上的时候，这里，就是我就住的地方
When I'm not in battle, this, is where I live.
MOD covert operations HQ.
国防部的秘密行动总部
如果太紧了就告诉我，虽然我觉得不会...
Let me know if it gets too tight and I don't think that...
Bennett 是最近负责照看我的教授
Bennett is the latest professor to keep an eye on me.
We really erased(??)
- 我看起来很放松吗？  - 是的（？）
- Do I look relaxed? - For you (??), yes you do.
他尽他最大的努力让我有一种家的感觉
He does his best to make me feel at home
你看，Bennett 跟其他人不一样
You see, Bennett's different to the others.
到头来事情的关键是...
The key thing is the end...
比较有亲和力。我一开始就喜欢他
Less distant. I liked him from the start.
他总能让我开怀大笑
He makes me laugh.
...doesnt' underdeveloped one... (??)
Bennett 的其中一项职责是给我定期配药
It is one of Bennett's jobs to regulate my medication
让我一直保持健康
to keep me fit forever
同时，我觉得，也是在保我的命
and, I suppose to keep me alive
我很好奇，如果停止服用这些，会怎样
I wonder how it would be if I stop taking these
估计我可能快要发现了
I suppose I might be about to find out
我已经看过了你的档案...
I've had a look at your file, and...
Bennett 跟我说关于这些花费出现了大的争议
Bennett told me there's a big debate going on about the costs
他们能证明这些费用是正当的吗？
can they justify the expense?
谁说过这个？
Who said that?
尽量放松
Just relax yourself
这整件事让我忍不住会想
The whole thing has left me thinking
这一切都是为了什么？
What's it all for?
我再也没有任何亲戚
I have no more relatives
也没有情绪波动
No emotional tides.
那些武装冲突和战区才是我唯一的宿命
These conflicts and war zones are my only destiny
或许这样最好
Perhaps its for the best
happy chap  his knee (??)
这跟PROBE有什么关系？
What's this gonna to do with PROBE?
哦，我明白了
Oh, I get it.
Haggard 知道你心里软
Haggard knows you've got a soft spot for the outsider
- 而且不会宣扬出去 - 闭嘴，Giles
- and you'll cause no fuss  - Shut up, Giles
大家下午好！
Good afternoon, everybody!
你们已经知道，首相和我在这间屋子发布了一个联合声明
As you know, the prime minister and I
made a joint statement in the house
是关于消减国防预算的
about the current defense cuts
今天我将会概括说明消减的是哪些费用
and today I'm going to outline exactly
where those cuts will fall
我想要强调一下面临的挑战...战略格局...
I want to focus on challenges... strategic landscape...
对预算新增加的制约条件
and new budget constraints
以及我们为应对这些挑战所持有的选项
and the choices we have in responding to these challenges
另外谈谈彻底重塑国防水平的机遇
And, the opportunities that exist
to fundamentally reshape the defence....
先生们，这一直不是一个容易做出的决定
Gentlemen, this has not been an easy decision
它就不应该走成现在这样
It should never have come to this.
但已经这样了。困难时期大家都得勒紧裤腰带
But it has. In times of austerity
we must all tighten our belts.
他会平静地离开吗？
Will he go quietly?
他是个战士，是个值得尊敬的人
He is a soldier. He is an honourable man.
我很肯定，给点时间，他会(??)
I'm sure, given time, he'll GUN?? intent to do it.
这事必须做的利落，做得干净
This must be quick, and it must be clean.
这个小实验已经耗费太多人力物力了
This little experiment has cost enough already.
好了，少校。你一直都不赞成这事，我感激这一点
Yeah, all right, Major.
I appreciate you never approved of any of this.
我们还是展现一点尊重，行吗？
Let's show some respect, shall we?
他也是个人
He is human.
勉强而已
Barely
步骤都安排好了，会由 PROBE 的 Shaw 博士来处理
The procedure is all in place
and will be handled by Dr. Shaw at the PROBE.
抱歉
Sorry.
PROBE?
别担心，长官。她会谨慎处理的
Don't worry, Sir. Shel'l be discreet.
是，这些东西会杀人
Yeah, these things are killing
- 嗨，你的日常菜单  - 男孩，谢谢你！
- Hi, you usual menu  - Boy, thank you!
怎样？
Well?
I don't look so surprised.
我看起来好像并不感到意外
有些事你并不知道，Liz
There are things you don't know, Liz.
PROBE 的箱子里有没有什么神奇物件
Is there anything in the PROBE box of tricks
...能够搞定这事儿的？
that might ... do the job?
Pasty! 搞定这事儿?
Patsy! Do the job?
你把下士说得像是一种机器似的
You make the corporal sound like some machine.
抱歉
Sorry.
You can take the girl out of the ministry (??)
But you can't take the ministry out of the girl.
怎样
Well?
你总这么折腾
Your relentless
William 紧盯着你要进展吧
William's breathing down your neck again.
别担心
Don't worry.
我肯定可以在 PROBE 的仓库里找到能点什么
I'm sure we'llfind something in the PROBE store.
你是在找什么时间循环转换器吗？
So you are looking for a time loop converter?
对
Yeah
我有种感觉我们可以找到一个容量足够的(?)
I'm gonna freak we're going to find one of those
with enough capacity to contain the courtfor(??)
库房里面有一个这样的设备
There was such a device in the storage hold.
不是我
It wasn't me.
是我
It was me
- 盒子！ - 是的。你好，Shaw 博士
- Box!  - Yes. Hello, Dr. Shaw.
是你，一个盒子
It's you. In a box
老天，它能用了！
My God, it works!
你把它修好了！
You fixed it!
左边第二区域
Second island on the left.
好主意，盒子
Good thinking, Box
谢谢你
Thank you
Liz?
在这里
In here
噢，盒子并不只是会说话啊
Oh box does more than just talking.
对的，盒子并不只是个盒子
Oh yes. Box is more than just a box.
记得这个吗？
Remember this?
我怎么能忘？1995年，对吧
How could I forget? 1995, wasn't it?
把那个女巫救活了？
Bringing that witch back to life?
你确定这个能行？
You sure this will work?
我是说，下士的事是如何能够抑制
I mean, the corporal is about containment
- 正确  - 我没跟你说话
- Positive.  - I wasn't talking to you.
你还有其它的想法？
You have any second thoughts?
这可是政府组织的行刑
This is a government organised execution
我对此觉得很不舒服
and I feel very uncomfortable about it
你好，是 Charlie 吗，Charlie Reynish?
Hello, is that Charlie, Charlie Reynish?
你好，请讲
Hello, speaking
我是 Bennett 教授，在国防部工作
I'm Professtor Bennett, from the MOD.
我是你兄弟 Paul 的朋友
And I'm a friend of your brother Paul.
- Paul？ 他已经死了  - 不不，他没死
- Paul? Paul's dead  - No, no, he's not dead.
我没有时间解释，你必须到这里来，马上
I don't have time to explain. You must get here now.
Paul，你已经到了
Paul, you're here ready.
是啊，自己的葬礼可不想迟到，对吧？
Well, wouldn't want to be late for my own funeral, would I?
恐怕，有个人要见见你，Paul
I fear, got somebody to meet you, Paul.
- 下士 7891-阿尔法 - 我知道
- Corporal 7891-Alpha  - I know.
Charlie是你的弟弟，Paul
Charlie's your brother, Paul.
不太像个棺材啊(?)
Not much of a coffin (??)
Johnson少校吧，我估计
Major Johnson, I pursue?
Shaw 博士
Dr. Shaw.
在这里等
Wait here
我们准备好了我会派人来叫你
I'll send somebody to fetch you when we're ready.
Bennett，Shaw博士来了
Bennett, Dr. Shaw is here.
- 你是谁?  - 我是 Charlie
- Who are you?  - I'm Charlie.
- 你在这里做什么？ - 我来带他回家
- What are you doing here? - I'll come to take him home
什么，你什么意思？ 你不能带他回去
What, what would you mean? You cant take him home.
Shaw 博士，这里！
Dr. Shaw. In here!
见鬼这里发生了什么？
What the hell happened in here?
我也想知道
Wish I knew.
Bennett，你做了些啥啊？
Bennett, what the hell have you done?
一件我很早之前就该做的事
Something I should have done a long time ago.
Liz.
- 他们会跟踪我们  - 我又不傻
- They will be tracking us  - I'm not stupid
似乎你已经失去了对局面的控制，少校
You seem to have lost control with the situation, Major.
- 你打算怎么做？  - 找到他
- What are you going to do about it?  - Find him
我并不经常给人第二次机会
I don't often give people second chances
不过我觉得我可以信任你，少校
but I think I can trust you, Major.
不要让我失望
Don't let me down
明白，都交给我吧
Understood. Leave it with me
- 怎么，Pasty？  - Liz，这里还有些情况
- Yes, Pasty? - Liz, there's something more.
喝吗？
Drink?
不了谢谢
No thanks
记得这个地方吗？
Remember this place?
他们会找到我们的，你知道吗
They're going to find us, you know
没必要再让 PROBE 参与了，你可以回基地去
Theres no need for PROBE anymore.
You can return to base.
不，Pasty，我要留在这里
No, Patsy. I'm staying here.
我们不能让你的情绪牵涉进来，Liz
We can't forge your emotional state
to come into play here, Liz
我明白这件事情上你也没有退路了
I understand your back's up against the wall on this one
但你需要我
But you need me
你说得对
You're right
但还是少校主导
But the major is in charge
我听说下士有消息，不过是搞砸了，是吗？
I heard about the corporal,
but of a shambles, don't you think?
所以，让我直说吧，是你把他弟弟扯进来的
So, let me get this straight. You led his brother in.
在当时的情况下这么做是对的
It was the right thing to do under the circumstances
Charlie 有权知道他兄弟还活着
Charlie deserves to know that his brother is still alive.
但在目前的情况下，这就是瞎搞
But under the circumstances, this is now a right fuck up
- 他们俩一起逃跑了！  - 我并不知道他会带武器
- They're both on the run!  - I didn't know he'd be armed.
更重要的是，少校
More importantly, Major
为什么下士被告知他弟弟已经死了？
why was the corporal told that Charlie was dead?
那跟我没关系
That had nothing to do with me.
是我的某位前任，Shaw 博士
It was one of my predecessors, Dr. Shaw
天大的错误，我现在知道了
A big mistake, I can see that now.
好了，别废话了
Okey, enough talk
恕我先告辞，我还得去找到下士的踪迹
Now if you excuse me, I have to find the corporal
我相信你不会挡我的路吧
I trust you won't stand in my way
你可以信任我的，少校
You can trust me, Major.
只要你做的是正确的
If you do the right thing
他们有把枪，老天
They have a gun, for Christ's sake
Bennett， 你让我别无选择
Bennett, you left me no choice.
我得先将你逮捕起来
I'm placing you under arrest
- 我找到车了  - 太好了！
- I found the car. - Excellent!
我这就来
I'm on my way.
这里没怎么变
This doesn't change much.
他们跟我说你得了癌症
They told me you had cancer.
是，这倒是实话
Yeah, that much is true.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
那，你怎么找到我的？
So, how did you find me?
- 是教授  - Bennett 吗？
- The professor.  - Bennett?
你撒谎...啊！
You're lying...Ah!
我需要我那些药
I need my meds.
准备好了？
Ready?
看到了吧，我不服用药片会怎么样？
See what happens when I don't take my pills?
跟我没喝酒的时候基本一样
You're much the same if I don't have a drink
你想要达到什么目的，？？？
What did you hope to achieve,
storming in old guns blazing?
我没有太多时间了，没法理智
I didn't have much time to be rational.
你想从我这里得到什么？
What do you want from me?
不是这个
Not this.
我曾经失去了你
I lost you once before.
我永远不会原谅我自己
I would never forgive myself.
如果我不能，至少得尝试一下
If I didn't, at least try.
我以为...
I thought...
带你来这个地方
by bringing you to this place
我们至少会有五分钟的宁静，免得...
we'd at least have five minutes peace before...
对不起
I'm sorry.
你是我仅有的了
You're all I have.
不
No
该说对不起的是我
It's me who should be sorry
我可以出击了
I'll go in.
视野清晰，长官
I've got clear view, sir.
听我命令
On my command
Shaw 博士，你在干什么？
Dr. Shaw, what are you doing?
这有点太极端了吧，少校？
It's a bit extreme, isn't it, Major?
我没得选择
I have no choice.
- 他开始移动了，长官  - 开枪
- He's on the move, sir - Fire
我会同 Bennett 谈的
I'll talk to Bennett.
应该能争取一点时间，然后...
that should buy some time and then...
也许会给你安排一个安全屋
maybe you can put it in a safe house
Charlie!
什么意思，你射偏了？
What do you mean, you missed?
下士怎么样了？
What about the corporal?
- 他在移动，长官  - 狗屎！
- He's on the move, Sir.   - Shit!
Roman, 停手，我们跟进
Roman let it go. We're moving in.
我们会确保给他一个体面的葬礼
We make sure we give him a decent burial.
是的
Yes
至少这点我们可以做
The least we can do.
长官，这边
Sir, over here.
有个隧道，长官
A tunnel, Sir.
看起来一直通到村子里了，长官
It looks like it goes all the way to the village, Sir
好，你们几个，到这里
Right, you lot, over here.
Haggard wrote like this.(??)
我还以为你已经掌控住了局面
I thought you had this under control
逃跑一次就够糟的了，但又来一次？
Escaping once is bad enough, but twice?
这都是什么执行能力？
What kind of operation is running here?
看起来像是动画片一样
looks very mickey mouse.
- 我明白你一开始  - 不，我觉得你不明白，Pasty
- I understand your first...
- No, I don't think you do understand Patsy
我正要给首相做汇报
I'm about to brief the prime minister
我还得避而不谈这个话题
I'm going to have to skirt around the fact that
我们搞砸了一个如此简单的任务
we've screwed up such a simple task
我不知道你怎么想，但我还是尽力想保住自己的饭碗的
Don't know about you, but I'm rather keen to keep my job
赶紧找到问题要害，鞭子甩响一点
Now get the grip, crack the whip
咱们别让这个乱局搞得全部里都知道了(??)
let's get this little mess wrapped up minister
你好像挺意外？
You looked surprised
其实并不
Not really
我就知道在这里可以找到你
I expected to find you here.
他们会找到你的，Paul
They'll take you, Paul.
你知道吗？我注意到了
You know what? I'd noticed.
更糟糕的是...
Its worse than that
我的丈夫想要你死
My husband wants you dead
我改变不了什么
Doesn't change anything
但我欠你的
but I owe it to you.
我需要我的药片
I need my meds.
你弄疼我了
You're hurting me
你们找到他了？
Have you found him?
并没有
Not exactly
那你为什么在这里
Why are you here?
我很迷茫
I'm lost.
你怎么找到Charlie 的？
So how did you find Charlie?
家庭的所有详请都在档案记录里
All the family details 're on the records
我以为只是让我们见见面
I thought if they could just meet.
这个就是
So this is it
只够三天的了
Just 3 days left
这就是有名的火星物质
This is a famous martian compound.
没有了这个，下士就死定了
Without this, the corporal is dead
我并不介意告诉你
I don't mind telling you.
对于当前这种无望的局面，我真的很担心
I'm really worried about this hopelessness
没时间焦虑了，我们必须把他弄回实验室
Theres no time for anxiety,
we have to get him back to the lab
不用担心我，教授
Don't worry about me, prof.
Paul.
你欺骗我！
You lied to me!
没事
It's all right
我是Shaw 博士，Liz
I'm Dr. Shaw, Liz.
你跟我说他已经死了
You told me he was dead
我们必须保护你，这都是为了你好
We had to protect you, it was done in your best interest.
你们杀害了他
You murdered him!
你没事吧？
Are you all right?
把它给我
Give them to me
- 并不在这里！  - 给我药片！
- They're not here.  - Give me the pills!
我这是怎么回事？像烧起来了
What's happening to me? It burns!
你处于一个很不稳定的状态，你需要我们
You are in very volatile state. You need us.
- 这还只是第一阶段  - 最重要是什么，Paul？
- This is only phase 1  - What is vital, Paul?
最重要是你回到实验室，我们可以将你稳定下来
It's vatal we get you back to the lab,
where we can get you stablized.
- 我不相信你！ - 你的身体要崩溃了，就全完了
- I don't trust you!  - Your body is giving up, its over.
闭嘴
Shut up
闭嘴，闭嘴
Shut up, shut up
- 这么说你也是他们一伙的？  - 不！我只是想帮忙
- So you ARE one of them?  - No! I'm only trying to help
我没想到你会这么生气，很抱歉
I had no idea you'v gone so mad, I'm sorry.
别担心，Shaw 博士
Don't worried, Dr. Shaw.
我的队伍会找到他，对付他
my team will find him and deal with him
不，不要用枪
No, no guns
风险太大
too risky
那...
so,
我们完全不了解，我们在对付的是什么
We have no idea of what were dealing with
正是
Exactly
下士遗留下来一点皮肤
The corporal has left some skin
至少我可以拿去做几个实验
so at least I can run some tests
我回来啦
I'm home.
他仍然在逃
He is still on the run
不过射杀了我们两个人
But he shot two of our men
所以我们把局面控制住了
So we had this under control.
老天啊
Dear god
一小片皮肤就能这样
One piece of skin can do that
是的
Yes
所以他就是个倒计时的炸弹
and he's a ticking time bomb
- 你要去哪儿？  - 我必须去重新校正一下椅子
- Where are you going?  - I have to recalibrate the chair.
- 下士那边怎么办？  - 他会来找我们的
- What about the corporal?  - He'll find us
- 那，我们就等着？  - 不会等太久
- So, we wait?  - Not for long.
Liz!
糟了
Shit
燃烧瓶？
Molotov cocktail (??)
我还以为这事会很简单
I thought this was gonna be simple
到底要搞多久？
How long can it be?
停下
Stop
别把它收起来
Don't put that away
长官？
Sir
怎么样？
Well?
还没消息
Nothing yet
你们他NND怎么还没找到他？
Why the bloody hell haven't you found him?
Haggard，我就说重点
Look, Haggard. I'll come to the point
你推荐你们 PROBE 的能人来做这事
You show your chunks of PROBE up to this.
但你们真的清楚我们在对付什么吗？
You do realize what were dealing with?
长官，我很清楚目前的情况
I am well aware, sir, of whats at stake
而且我不觉得有任何人比 Shaw 博士更有资格
and I can't think of anyone more qualified than Dr. Shaw.
希望你是对的
I hope you're right.
最后的六小时
for all last 6.
哦，不，糟了
Oh,  no, shit
Not to implode (??) function to the elemental array
好主意
Good idea.
- 有什么消息  - 我们做了些测试
- Any news? - We run some tests ??
结果呢？
And?
不妙
It's bad.
很不妙
Very bad.
你觉得我做错了，是吧？
You think I made a mistake, don't you?
你把他变成了一头怪兽
You've turned him into a monster.
暴风雨前的宁静
The calm before the storm.
我们准备好了
Now we're ready.
你在哪里？
Where are you?
目标已找到
Target located.
Shaw 博士，你是对的
Dr. Shaw you're right
这个定时炸弹
A ticking time bomb
已经露面了
has gone public
- 准备好面包车 - 是，长官
- Get the van ready - Sir
(Johnson 少校)
(Major Johnson)
少校
Major.
你找到了吗？在哪儿？
You found it? where?
牧羊从？  （位于伦敦西区，临近伦敦富人区肯辛顿区）
Shepherds Bush?
快。好，我们到那里汇合
Quicky. ok, we will meet you there.
我们要去购物了
We're going shopping.
你哪儿也不能去
You're not going anywhere.
如果这事出了纰漏，就由你负责了
If all this goes tits up, you're in charge
你在哪儿，我很好奇
Where are you, I wonder?
糟糕
Shit
我刺探了通讯网络
I meant intercepting of transmission.
Johnson 少校刚刚知会了 Haggard
Major Johnson has just informed Haggard
说下士有一名女人质
that the corporal has a female hostage.
我们刚才还以为事情不可能进一步恶化了
Just when we thought it couldn't get any worse.
我们只需要确保我们的汇报是全面的
We just need to make sure that we've got a thorough briefing
我猜我们已经找到他了
I presume we found him then
如之前所料，是他找到了我们
As expected, sir, he found us
而且还有点别的情况
and there's something else
So?
什么？
Haggard，说话吞吞吐吐可不像你的风格
Haggard, its not like you to beat around the bush
是 Josie，长官
It's Josie, Sir
各就各位，先生们
Positions, gentlemen
动静小点，我们不想惊动平民
Nice and discreet.
We don't want to disturb the natives,
下士也绝不能看见我们
and the corporal must not see us.
出去
Out.
马上
Now.
- 你他妈的在做什么？  - 把活干完
- What the fuck are you doing? - Finishing the job.
坐下
Sit.
你受伤了
You're hurt.
比你能想到的严重
More than you can imagine.
保持原位别动
Hold your positions.
他把她带去哪里了？
Where'd he taken her?
保安室
Security office.
你是对的
You were right.
他早计划好了
He has a plan.
他能看到我们的任何动作
He can see everything that we do
好吧
Well
那是什么？
What's that?
那是把椅子
That's the chair.
它是我们问题的答案，前提是得让他坐上去
Its the answer to all our prayers,
if we can get him to sit in it.
长官
Sir.
Williams 太太的号码
Mrs Williams' number
Reasoning of what she said? (??)
祝好运
Good luck.
快接
Answer it.
- 你好？  -Williams 太太，你没事吧
- Hello?   - Mrs Williams, are you all right?
噢，我没事
Oh, I'm fine
下士在那边吧，我要同他通话
Is corporal there now, I need to talk to him
他手里有枪
He has a gun.
是 Johnson 少校，他要同你通话
It's Major Johnson. He wants to talk to you.
- 少校  - 下士
- Major  - Corporal
想从我们这里得到什么就直说吧
Is there anything you need from us?
没，没什么我想要的
No, there's nothing I need.
- 你确定吗？  - 我说过了，没有
- Are you sure?  - I said nothing.
你要把 Williams 太太带去哪里？
Where are you going to take Mrs Williams?
Williams 太太将会亲眼看到烟花
Mrs Williams will be watching the fireworks first hand.
下士，你的诉求我们明白
Corporal, you've made your point.
但这里有数千人陷入风险，你必须停止，士兵
There are thousands of people at risk.
You've got to stop this now, soldier.
但我不再是个士兵了，少校
But I'm no longer a soldier, Major.
秘书处的人开除了我，还记得吗？
They in the secretary discharged me, Remember?
- 现在听着...  - 不，少校，现在由我发号施令
- Now listening...
- No, major, I'm giving you the orders now.
什么也不要做
Do nothing.
坐回去
Sit back.
看着
and watch
除非你期望你的手上沾上 Josie 的血
unless you want Josie's blood on your hands.
- 你不能伤害她  - 你已经听到我说的了
- You won't hurt her.  - You heard what I said.
队伍已经准备好了，长官
The men are ready, sir.
让他们保持原地别动
Keep them where they are.
等我们发现他有所动作再说
Till we know  he attack, for now
各位保持原位
Hold on your positions.
是的，我知道！我们就快没时间了
Yes, I know!  We're running out of time.
对不起
Sorry
这事儿已经超出我的极限了(??)
You could get out of my depth on this one
我们都是，少校
We all are, major.
我们都是
We all are.
Liz
那是什么？
What's that?
是盒子
It's box.
一个老朋友送的礼物
A gift from an old friend.
看起来是个礼物
Something looking present
它有什么作用吗？
Does it serve any purpose?
它让我一直保持警醒
It keeps me on my toes.
有什么事吗，盒子？
Anything, box?
Liz，我要跟你说说情况
Liz, I need to talk to you.
失陪一下，少校
Excuse me, major.
- 你要去哪儿？  - 你看好那把椅子
- Where are you going?  - Take care of the chair.
左转
Go left.
上去
Up there.
- 你这是怎么了  - 你丈夫没告诉你？
- What's happening to you?
- Didn't your husband tell you?
国防部最致命的武器
The MOD's most lethal weapon
就要以最惊人的方式退役了
is being decommissioned in the most spectacular style
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
是个男孩
A boy.
你有孩子吗？
Do you have any children?
我知道你在想什么，Patricia
I know what you're thinking, Patricia
当大粪甩到风扇上...
when the shit hits the fan...
长官
Sir
噢，你...需要帮助
Oh you...need help.
我明白，长官
I understand, Sir.
你现在处于一个无解的境地
that you are in an impossible position.
我已经决定了
I made up my mind.
你确定就好，长官
If you're sure, Sir.
我确定，少校。去，把事情搞定
I am sure, major. And, get the job done.
明白，长官。我们会尽最大努力
Understood, Sir. We'll do our best.
所有成员进入
All the member going in.
Paul，你得放我走
Paul, you have to let me go.
你哪里也不能去
You're not going... anywhere.
立即停下。记得吗？
Sheer to stop. Remember?
得看清楚才能开枪
and only if you can get a clear shot
加油，少校
Come on, major.
伙计，听着
Men, listen
我们没有时间了
We've run out of time.
你听我命令行动
You move on my order.
记住
Remember,
不许伤下士性命，这很重要
Its vital to keep the corporal alive.
走
Go
糟糕！
Shit!
到头来也许你没有那么重要
Maybe you're not so valuable after all.
是首相
It's the PM.
我会打回给他
I'll call him back.
等等！
Wait!
把枪给我
Give me the gun.
都结束了
It's over.
她怀孕了
She's pregnant.
不
No.
是真的
It's true.
四个月了
4 months.
是个男孩
It's boy.
走
Go
那 Shaw 博士...
And Dr. Shaw...
我快没有时间了
I'm running out of time.
你快走
You go.
这是命令，士兵
That's a order, soldier.
有什么...好笑的？
What's so...funny?
我们的命运
Our fate.
以及捉弄我们的那只手
and the hand deals us.
你在说些什么？
What are you talking about?
我们俩都有点疯狂，是不是？
We're both a little crazy, aren't we?
你和我
You and me.
噢，得了
Oh, come on.
你知道我说的是什么吗？
You know what I'm talking about?
这一切都是为了什么？我听见自己在喊
What's it all for? I hear myself shout.
你弟弟 Charlie 早知道，对吧，Paul？
You brother Charlie knew it, didn't he, Paul?
他当然知道，Bennett 告诉他了
Of course he did. Bennett told him.
不仅仅是说这个
It was more than that.
虽然他知道他就要死了，但他继续前行
He kept going despite the fact
that he knew he was dying
来吧，Paul
Come on, Paul.
你可以做得更好
You're better than that.
来吧
Do it.
坐进来
Come in now.
盒子？
Box?
Shaw 博士
Doctor Shaw
什么，少校？
Yes, major?
我...我是想说...
I...I meant to say...
谢谢你
Thank you.
这什么意思，这就接管了？
What's this, a takeover bid?
Liz!
不是啊
No.
PROBE 只有一个老板
There is only one boss of PROBE.
感谢上帝终于结束了
Thank God its all over.
怎么了？
What's the matter?
什么事
What?
坐下
Sit down.
是什么？
What is it?
我在想...
I'm thinking...
of jack Quinn ??
什么？
What?
我在想可能是西班牙
I'm thinking it maybe Spain.
西班牙？噢，呵呵。你疯啦？
Spain? Oh, hehe. You mad?
那我怎么办？
What about me?
我想让你陪我一起去
I'd want you to come with me.
（花絮）
(后面字幕完全为机器听录结果)
hello everyone  nice and discreet
we don't want to disturb the natives
the couple must not know where here
its one of Bennetts jobs to keep me alive
No  no  its not
do less eyebrow
allowed to register my thighs
and feed it in any size
positions  gentlemen  the decisions
didnt even
this
in here
yeah
box is more than just
worst
my husband  to get
I guess
I presumably founded
but I'm just going by the door opening
don't go
I'm recording
its
oh  you should just
the fuck are you doing?
finishing the job
sit
a fucking  you do that shit
that you're going to eat something  and I don't don't tell me what hes going to do
Tell me  what are you cant do that